fortuneindia.com 2019-03-21

# Privacy Policy

_Last Updated on May 2_ _5, 2018_

_This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Business Media Private Limited (BMPL) collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User") in respect of the Sites and Mobile Applications and all internet and mobile based products and services offered by **BMPL**._

_"You" and / or "Your" and / or "User" shall include and mean the person who is accessing the aforesaid websites through any means available now and / or maybe available in the future._

_Governing Law and Meanings: -_

_These Terms of Use are being governed by the Laws of India and meaning of words used herein in connection with the use of the said website shall bear the meaning as may be envisaged and interpreted by the Information Technology Act, 2000 and any of its Amendment Acts._

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE GATHER ABOUT YOU?**

The information gathered when you interact with **BMPL** falls into two categories: 1) Personal information, which includes personal information you supply when you subscribe, order, complete a survey, register for one of our sites, enter a contest or provide your email address and 2) Non-personal information collected through technology, which includes tracking information collected by us as well as third parties.

**_Personal Information That You Give Us or Ask a Third Party to Share with Us_**

**Registration Information**

Registration for **BMPL** may require that you supply certain personal information, including a unique email address and demographic information (ZIP code, age, sex, household income, job industry and job title) to register.

You may register or enhance your profile by linking your Facebook or Google accounts on **BMPL**. By doing this, you are asking them to send us certain information from those social media accounts, and you are authorizing us to collect, store, and use what they send us in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Social media registration features may collect your IP address, the page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website.

You can disassociate your **BMPL** registration from third-party accounts any time.

Kindly note that **BMPL** shall not responsible for any information collected by the third party from you.

**User Generated Content and Public Activities (Including Comments and Reader Reviews)**

We offer you opportunities to engage in public activities on **BMPL**.com and other **BMPL** Services. "Public activities" are any actions you take on **BMPL** that are designed to be visible to other users, including comments, recommendations, reader reviews, ratings or any other items that you submit. Any information you disclose in your public activities, along with your screen name or ID, or any image or photo, becomes public and may be used by **BMPL** for online and offline promotional or commercial uses in any and all media. If you choose to engage in public activities, you should be aware that any personal information you submit can be read, collected and used by other users of these areas. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in the course of your public activities and we have no responsibility to publish, take down, remove or edit any of your public activities or submissions. For more information, see [Terms of Use](https://www.fortuneindia.com/terms-of-use).

Public activities may be included in our RSS feeds, APIs and other distribution formats. As a result, your public activities may appear on other websites, blogs, or feeds. Keep in mind that we are not responsible for any personal information you choose to make public via your public activities, and you agree that such sharing will be deemed to have been done by you, not **BMPL** including but not limited to sharing of information in your connected social media accounts.

When you share or recommend links to content on a third-party platform (such as Facebook, Google+ and Twitter), that action and any information you share will be covered by their privacy policy.

**Contests, Sweepstakes and Special Offers  
BMPL** collects personal information from you when you participate in sweepstakes, contests or special offers. If this information is also being collected by a third party other than **BMPL** , we will notify you at the same time. If you do not want any personal information shared, you should not participate in the sweepstakes, contest or special offer.

**Reader Surveys, Reader Panels and Market Research**  
**BMPL** may collect personal information from you in connection with voluntary surveys conducted via **BMPL**. Data may be collected through **BMPL** , on the phone or through the mail. The information you provide may be shared, but only in the aggregate, with advertisers and partners unless we notify you otherwise at the time of collection.  
Members of our Reader Panels agree to participate in surveys, polls or discussions about their readership of **BMPL** , their household/personal characteristics and their purchase behavior.

**Conferences and Live Events**  
We often receive information about attendees to our live events from sign-in and registration lists. We may share this information with event or promotion sponsors, in which case we will notify you when we collect the information.

**_Non-Personal Information Collected Using Technology_**

**Information Collected by Us Using Technology**

We use various internet technologies to manage **BMPL** and track use of the Services. Non-personal information that we collect using these technologies may be combined with other information about you.

**Device Information.**  We may collect non-personal information about the computer, mobile device or other device you use to access **BMPL** , such as IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language and other transactional information.

**Cookies, Beacons, Local Storage and Other Similar Technologies.**  We use "cookies," web beacons, tags and scripts, and other similar technologies including local storage objects such as HTML5. These technologies allow us to manage access to and use of the Services, recognize you and provide personalization, and help us understand how people use **BMPL**. You will not be able to access certain areas of our websites, including **BMPL** , if your computer does not accept cookies from us. We do not respond to browser-based "do not track" signals. For more detailed information about our use of cookies and local storage, and how to manage them, see  _Fortune India’s Cookie Policy_ at end of this page.

We may transmit non-personally identifiable website usage information to third parties in order to show you advertising for **BMPL** when you visit other sites. For more information about our third-party ad server, or to learn your choices about not having this non-personal information used to target ads to you, please [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/).

**Local Storage Objects**

We may use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML5 or Flash to collect and store information.

Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here:

<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>

**Analytics, Log Files and Reading History**

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses (the region or general location where your computer or device is accessing the internet), browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of **BMPL** , including a history of the pages you view.

We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, including customized Recommendations, advertising and currency display, to improve marketing, and to track access and use of   **BMPL** across the devices that you use to access **BMPL**.

We have hired third parties to provide us information, reports and analysis about the usage, browsing patterns of our users. They may independently record the type of device and operating system you are using, general location information, as well as events that occur within our apps, such as how often you use our apps.

**Location Information.**  Some of our mobile applications can deliver content based on your current location if you choose to enable that feature of the app. If you enable the location-based feature, your current location will be stored locally on your device, which will then be used by the app. If you elect to have a location-based search saved to your history, we will store that information on our servers. If you do not enable the location-based service, or if an app does not have that feature, the app will not transmit to us, and we will not collect or store, location information.

The ads in our apps are not targeted to you based on your current GPS location, but they may be targeted to you based on your ZIP code or device's IP address.

**Third Parties**

Some of the services and advertisements included in **BMPL** , including on **BMPL** and within our mobile apps, are delivered or served by third-party companies, which may collect information about your use of **BMPL**.

These companies may place or recognize cookies, web beacons or other technology to track certain non-personal information about our website users. For example, in the course of serving certain advertisements, an advertiser may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser in order to collect certain information about your use of **BMPL**. For another example, an advertiser or ad server may also be able to collect your device’s unique identifier in the course of serving an ad. In many cases, this information could be used to show you ads on other websites based on your interests.

We do not have access to, nor control over, these third parties' use of cookies or other tracking technologies or how they may be used. For example, we use Google to serve advertisements onto **BMPL** , which use the Google Doubleclick cookie, and in some cases, a unique device identifier, to show you ads based on your visit to **BMPL** and other sites on the internet. You may opt out of the use of the Google Doubleclick cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences).

You have choices about the collection of information by third parties on our website. If you would like to opt-out of having interest-based ad targeting, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

Your access to our websites should not be affected if you do not accept cookies served by third parties.

**WHAT DO WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER ABOUT YOU?**

**Provide the Services You Request**

We use the information we gather about you to enable your use of **BMPL** and fulfil your requests for certain products and services, such as sending out electronic newsletters and enabling you to participate in and renew paid services, polls, contests and message boards.

**Statistical Analysis**

We perform statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of users of **BMPL** , and their subscribing and purchasing patterns, for product development purposes and to generally inform advertisers about the nature of our subscriber base. We use this information for analysis purposes, including analysis to improve customer relationships.

**Customizing Your Experience**

We use the information that we collect to allow advertising to be targeted to the users for whom such advertising is most pertinent. We also use this information to customize certain features of **BMPL** to provide you with an enhanced experienced based on the type of device you are using to access **BMPL** , and in certain cases, provide you with requested services.

**Relevant Advertising**

We may use demographic and preference information to allow advertising on **BMPL** Service to be targeted to the users for whom they are most pertinent. This means users see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer's experience and the effectiveness of the ads. We disclose information to third parties only in aggregate or de-identified form.

**Email Newsletters**

**BMPL** will periodically send you email newsletters or promotional email about services offered by **BMPL** and its advertisers. For details about **BMPL** email, please see below:

### WHAT IS OUR EMAIL POLICY?

We will not send you marketing messages if you have unsubscribed. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by following the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each email. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address for commercial purposes without your permission. However, we will only share your email id with our registered partners in conformance with law. If you feel you have received an email from us in error, please contact [marketing@fortuneindia.com](mailto:marketing@fortuneindia.com)

**Email Newsletters.**  If you no longer wish to receive a specific newsletter, follow the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each newsletter.

**Survey Email.**  We may invite you to participate in user surveys asking for feedback on Fortune India and existing or prospective products and services, as well as information to better understand our users. User surveys greatly help us to improve our Services, and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties, except in aggregate form.

**Emails from You.**  If you send us an email, we will use your email address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

**Email This Article Feature.**  Addresses you provide in the “Email” share feature may be saved for your convenience for future articles you may wish to email; but they are not used for any other purpose, and will not be shared with any third parties.

**WITH WHOM DO WE SHARE THE INFORMATION THAT WE GATHER?**

**Within BMPL**

If you have registered to use **BMPL** , we will not sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address without your permission.

In the future, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses. In such transactions, we may include your information among the transferred assets.

**Third Parties**

We also share information about our audience in aggregate or de-identified form. Nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to restrict our use or sharing of aggregated or de-identified information in any way.

If you are a print subscriber, we may exchange or rent your name and mailing address (but not your email address) and certain other information, such as when you first subscribed to **BMPL** with other reputable companies that offer marketing information or products through direct mail. If you prefer that we do not share this information, you may opt-out by emailing us at [marketing@fortuneindia.com](mailto:marketing@fortuneindia.com) or write to us at: **BMPL** Pvt. Ltd. Pioneer House, 3rd Floor, Plot No 45-50, Block-A, Sector 16, Noida – 201301, India  
Please include your account number and phone number in the body of your email or letter, and include "Opt-out" in the subject line.

We may share information about attendees to our live events with sponsors or other third parties. If so, we will notify you when you provide us the information.

**Service Providers**

We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing, ad serving, shipping, email distribution, list processing and analytics or promotions management. We provide these companies only with the information they need to perform their services. These service providers are restricted from using personal information in any way other than to provide services for **BMPL** , and they may not share, resell or use the data for their own direct marketing purposes.

We reserve the right to disclose your opt-out information to third parties so they can suppress your name from future solicitations, in accordance with applicable laws. We may occasionally release personal information as required by law, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena.

**HOW DO I CHANGE OR UPDATE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

**Manage Your BMPL Account in the My Account Area.**  You may review and update your **BMPL** membership or account information and access your transaction history in the My Account area. We will respond to inquiries regarding deletion of data within a reasonable timeframe.

**Data Retention.**  We will retain your information for at least as long as your account is active, as needed to provide you services or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. As a matter of course, we will delete personally identifiable information associated with accounts that have been inactive for at least 15 years. 

**HOW DO I OPT-OUT?**

If, at any time, you prefer not to receive email marketing information from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each email.

If you experience difficulty with the unsubscribe process, feel free to contact us at [marketing@fortuneindia.com](mailto:marketing@fortuneindia.com) and provide your email address along with the name of the newsletter from which you would like to unsubscribe.

**Mail or Telephone Promotions**

If, at any time, you prefer not to receive mail or telephone solicitations originated by **BMPL** Home Delivery Department, or if you prefer that we do not share this information with third parties for marketing purposes, please email us at [marketing@fortuneindia.com](mailto:marketing@fortuneindia.com) or write to us at **BMPL** Pvt. Ltd. Pioneer House, 3rd Floor, Plot No 45-50, Block-A, Sector 16, Noida – 201301, India. Please include your account number and phone number in the body of your email or letter, and put "Opt-out" in the subject line.

It is further provided that if you wish **BMPL** to delete your data provided by you to **BMPL** you are requested to send an email to [marketing@fortuneindia.com](mailto:marketing@fortuneindia.com) by expressly stating that the data provided by you be deleted. However, **BMPL** can only delete the data you provided to **BMPL** and this deletion shall in no manner deem to be deletion of your data that you may have provided to your linked third party social media accounts.

**Use of Third Party Personal Information**

If you choose to use "email this article" or give a Gift subscription, we require the recipient’s name and email address. We will automatically send them a one-time email about the service. **BMPL** does not store this information.

**IS MY INFORMATION PROTECTED?**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, technical and administrative controls to protect the information. Please note that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure.

**OTHER INFORMATION**

**Compliance With Legal Process**

We may access, preserve and disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of **BMPL** ; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).

**Changes to This Policy**

We evaluate this privacy policy periodically in light of changing business practices, technology and legal requirements. As a result, it is updated from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. If we make a significant or material change in the way we use or share your personal information, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice.

**Fortune India’s Cookie Policy**

BMPL is committed to being transparent about how we use cookies on our sites and the technologies that underpin their collection and usage.

**Why cookies are important**

Cookies help make your online experience more efficient and relevant to your interests. For instance, they are used to remember your preferences on sites you visit often, to remember your user ID and the contents of your shopping baskets, and to help you navigate between pages more efficiently.

Please read below for more detail.

  * **What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small file, or files on your computer, phone, or other device with a browser to save snippets of text for reference by the website you are visiting.

All cookies have expiration dates in them that determine how long they stay in your browser.

  * **Session cookies**

These are temporary cookies that expire (and are automatically erased) whenever you close your browser. For example, we use session cookies to grant access to content and enable commenting (things you have to log in to do).

  * **Persistent cookies**  

These usually have an expiration date and so stay in your browser until they expire, or until you manually delete them. For example we use persistent cookies for functionality including the "Stay logged-in" tick box. We also use persistent cookies to better understand usage patterns so that we can improve the site for our customers.

We've included more details below to help you understand what kinds of cookies and other technologies we use.

**Other technologies linked to cookies**

There are other technologies which can seem similar to cookies, but are not the same, including pixels and site tags. These pixels or tags can be used to retrieve information such as your device type or operating system, IP address, time of visit, etc. (Please see our [Privacy Policy](https://www.fortuneindia.com/privacy-policy) for more details on the types of information that may be collected.) They are sometimes used to create or access the cookies on your browser, but are not cookies themselves. Only cookies which you can control will appear in the cookie consent tool.

**What types of cookies do our sites use and why?**

**Categories of Use**

| 

**Description**  
  
---|---  
  
Authentication

| 

If you’re logged in to Fortune India, cookies help us show you the right information and personalize your experience.  
  
Security

| 

We use cookies to enable and support our security features, and to help us detect malicious activity and violations of our User Agreement.  
  
Preferences, features and services

| 

Cookies can tell us which language you prefer and what your communications preferences are. They can help you fill out forms more easily. They also provide you with features, insights, and customized content in conjunction with our plugins. You can learn more about plugins in our Privacy Policy.  
  
Advertising

| 

We may use cookies to show you relevant advertising both on and off the website. We may also use a cookie to learn whether someone who saw an ad later visited and took an action (e.g. downloaded a white paper or made a purchase) on the advertiser’s site. Similarly, our partners may use a cookie to determine whether we’ve shown an ad and how it performed, or provide us with information about how you interact with ads. We may also work with a partner to show you an ad on or off the website, such as after you’ve visited a partner’s site or application.  
  
Performance, Analytics and Research

| 

Cookies help us learn how well our site and plugins perform in different locations. We also use cookies to understand, improve, and research products, features, and services, including when you access Fortune India from other websites, applications, or devices such as your work computer or your mobile device.  
  
To ensure compliance with our policies, we restrict the use of third-party cookies to trusted partners of Fortune India. For example, we currently allow partners including:

  * Youtube for our multimedia platform and Doubleclick (Google) for our advertising platform;
  * We also use third party information from third party sources to enable us to deliver advertising. Establishing a particular audience demographic allows us to target advertising based on browsing behaviour stored in a cookie.

These sources are validated by the third party, not by us. Our advertising partners use cookies accompanying the adverts to enable them and their advertisers to monitor the effectiveness of their ads.

We may also use cookies and your IP address to discover general information about which pages on our sites you visit and the country, city or region in which you are located. We sometimes combine this with information provided to us by third parties, together this information enables you to be grouped with other people with similar interests and places you in a market segment, such as "technology", "Android Phone", or . We may then display advertisements which we believe people in your market segment will find relevant. We believe this makes the advertising more interesting and useful to you, and also helps us increase the value we get out of the site from our advertisers, and therefore ultimately gives us a greater ability to invest in great content for the benefit of all users.

We may also allow advertisers to use their own marketing data to target advertising campaigns on this website and as a result you may see advertising based upon website content you have been viewing on another website. For example, a retailer might use information about the products you browsed on their website in order to tailor their advert to you on this website. This information is not shared with us and we do not share information with the advertiser about your browsing of our website.

Below you'll find information and a link to our cookie consent tool to help you manage your cookie preferences.

**How can I delete or opt-out of cookies?**

You can opt out of cookies at any time by using our cookie consent tool.

This tool includes additional detail on the types of cookies used, what information is being collected and for what purpose. It also includes links to the privacy policies for each individual cookie, giving you the option to allow or block as you choose. When you refer to any one of these privacy policies you’ll find more information on the controls available to you, and your rights with respect to the personal information that these third parties access, collect and use about you.

Please note that we are not responsible for the content of other external websites. Your cookie consent preferences are accessible at any time at the bottom of all ABP website pages.

Alternatively, the following websites provide some useful information on how to do this, as well as about your rights under current data protection and privacy regulations.

For more information, please go to:

[http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) if you are based in the EU;

<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> if you are based in the US.

To opt out of cookies from Google: [ https://www.google.com/settings/ads](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)

If you want to delete or disable other browser cookies, see: [www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies)  or [https://www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/)
